BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nahuel Brandán

contact@nahuelbrandan.com | mahuelbrandan.com/en | L+54 9 3574 638119 | Oba / Arg inkedin.com/in/nahuelbrandan | jethub.com/nahuelbrandan | jethub.com/sers/6125910

ABOUT ME

+3 years of experience in software development, specialized on Python, including work in the aerospace industry. Collaborated effectively with various multidisciplinary teams. Strove to implement the best development practices, and improve technical documentation to ensure the reliability and scalability of the work. Graduated with a Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science.

EXPERIENCE

Satellogic 06/2022 - 09/2022

Backend Software Developer

Remote

Company specialized in the creation and use of earth observation satellites.

- Refactored an application into two separate entities, reducing coupling and improving maintainability.
- Contributed to improve code quality through regular code reviews and technical discussions.

Ascentio | Project: Sabia-Mar

08/2021 - 05/2022

Backend Software Developer

Remote

Satellite mission, with advanced technology for the study of the sea and the ocean.

- Developed contributions to satellite flight planning and communication modules, using technologies such as: Python, Docker, FastAPI and APIs.
- Created unit and integration tests, using tools like Robot Framework, Postman and Pytest.
- Documented about projects and development processes, using tools such: as LaTex and Markdown.

IncluIT | Project: Junar

03/2019 - 07/2021

Python Developer

Cba - Arg

- Developed and maintained the backend base code of the system, based on Python, Django, and DRF.
- Integrated Auth0 and Keycloak technologies as security layers in API management.
- Executed an upgrade of Django versions and others +15 dependencies, to reduce the technical debt.
- Optimized 30% performance in response time of the APIs, through cache management.
- Managed technical onboarding to +10 new developers, providing guidance and technical support.

EDUCATION

National University of Córdoba - Argentina

10/2018

B.S in Computer Science (Graduated)

Cba - Arg

Career with strong emphasis on programming, analysis and design of systems, databases and computer networks, combining a solid theoretical understanding with practical skills.

COURSES -

Platzi 01/2021 - Present

Complete more than 100 courses and in constant learning in the professional online academy called Platzi, on topics such as: soft skills, English, software development.

SKILLS

- · Programming languages: Python, C.
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch.
- Frameworks: Django, Django REST Framework, FastAPI, Robot Framework.
- Dev tools: Linux, REST API, Git, GitHub, Bash, Postman, Auth0, Docker, Celery.

LANGUAGES

• English: B1 intermediate.

Spanish: Native.